# **CLARA CUARTAS**

UI/UX DESIGNER

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Rionegro Colombia

#### PHONE

3004544470

#### **EMAIL**

clara.isabel.cuartas@gmail.com

#### LINKS

<u>linkedin</u>

Website

#### SKILLS

Wireframe Creation, Mockups, and Prototypes (High and Low Fidelity)

. . . . .

Responsive and Adaptive Design

• • • • •

Design Systems

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

User Research

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

Persona Analysis and Creation

. . . . .

User Testing and Feedback

. . . . .

User Flow and Journey Mapping

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

Figma

• • • • •

Sketch

• • • • 0

Adobe Illustrator

• • • •

Adobe Photoshop

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

Adobe XD

. . . . .

Empathy

• • • • •

Effective and Assertive Communication

• • • •

#### PROFILE

Hi! I'm Clara Cuartas, a graphic designer with over ten years of experience in UI/UX. I enjoy creating digital experiences that are both functional and accessible. With a solid background in psychology and experience as a teacher, I have a unique perspective for understanding and addressing users' needs in a close and empathetic manner. My goal is to design solutions that truly make a difference in people's lives. Professional Experience Throughout my career, I have worked on designing interfaces for web and mobile devices, honing my skills in UI and UX. My background in graphic design and my constant updating on the latest UI/UX trends allow me to offer creative and effective solutions. I deeply appreciate teamwork and have led various projects, always with the aim of creating intuitive and accessible digital experiences. I strive to communicate clearly and guide teams to ensure that users' needs are always a priority. Academic and Teaching Background In addition to being a graphic designer, I have a background in psychology, which complements my user-centered design approach. For five years, I was a university lecturer in personal development, which allowed me to develop assertive communication and leadership skills. These experiences enable me to approach design comprehensively, ensuring that each project is empathetic, creative, and accessible.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

### Facilitator Instructor, Colegiatura Colombiana.

Medellín

Jan 2018 — Jan 2023

### Entrepreneur, Autónomo

Medellín

Jan 2021 — Nov 2023

Facilitator of Being and Instructor Dream Designer Psychologist in Training

#### Co-Founder, Trusty To You

Medellín

Mar 2017 — Jul 2021

Trusty, We Transform Business Objects into Real Value. Digital Strategy. www.trusty.com.co

# **Project Coordinator, Estrategia Conker**

Medellín

2015 - 2016

#### Sales Representative, ALIANZA INFINITUM

Medellín

May 2015 — Aug 2016

#### Manager, TIENDA PLASMA

Medellín

Nov 2013 — May 2015

### **Designer, PLASMA NODO**

Medellín

Aug 2009 — Nov 2013

## **Graphic Designer, PWV CREATIVOS**

Medellín

Oct 2008 — Aug 2009

Team Collaboration

. . . . .

Conflict Resolution

. . . . 0

Flexibility

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

Critical Thinking

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

Creative Thinking and Continuous Improvement

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

Time Management

• • • • •

Feedback Reception and Delivery

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

#### LANGUAGES

English

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

#### **EDUCATION**

## Graphic Communicator, Graphic Design, Corporación Universitaria Minuto de Dios

Jan 2005 — Jan 2009

## Psychology, Psychology, Católica del Norte Fundación Universitaria

#### COURSES

# Creating high-fidelity prototypes and designs in Figma, Google

May 2024

# Fundamentals of User Experience (UX) Design, Google

May 2024

# First Steps in the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, Ideate, Google

Mar 2024

# **Creating Wireframes and LowFidelity Prototypes, Google**

Apr 2024

### **UX Research, Google**

Jan 2024

### Concepts of Interface Design, Platzi

Sep 2023

# General English Program (Level II - Intermediate), ILSC Education Group - Australia

Nov 2022 — Oct 2023

### Life Coaching Certification, Udemy

Jul 2020

# Tools for Personal Well-being, Universidad EAN

May 2020

# Diplama in Facilitation of Systemic, Individual and Collective Development, Colegiatura Colombiana

Dec 2017

### Diploma: "The Artist as a Brand", UPB

Apr 2017

# Training: Leadership Mastery, Colegiatura Colombiana

Oct 2014